Botany Department Records 1938-1957
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Botany Department Records
1938-1957
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 248
1 linear feet 2 containers
Includes correspondence, minutes, reports, budgets, recruiting and department graduate student information.
Organizational History:
Washington Agricultural College first employed a botanist in 1893. A Department of Botany and Zoology came into existence in about 1895. A separate Botany Department was organized in 1907, and continues to the present (2000AD). The Botany faculty has included many well-known botanical scientists.
Further documentation of the Botany Department can be found at the University Libraries, chiefly in the form of personal papers of various members of the faculty. See also WSU Publications 37.
Correspondence, minutes, reports, budgets, recruiting inforation, and information regarding graduate, students, including placement of same, to and from the Department of Botany. Of particular interest is the correspondence of Winslow R. Hatch, Chairman of the Division of Biological Sciences, and early correspondence regarding the development of the Prairie Strip Administration.
The records are arranged in subject files, ordered alphabetically.
The Collection is open for research use.
Records of the Washington State University Department of Botany were transferred to the University Libraries in 1988 by Botany department personnel (UA1988-34).
Hatch, Winslow Roper, 1908---Archives
Washington State University. Botany Department--Archives; State College of Washington. Botany Department.; State College of Washington. Division of Biological Sciences.; Washington State University. Botany Department--Records and correspondence; Washington State University. Botany Department--Curricula--History
Botany--Study and teaching (Higher)--Washington (State)--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- "A" Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual Report, 1946-1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- "B" Miscellanous, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bausch & Lomb Optical Co., 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Books, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Botany Courses, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Botany Greenhouse, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Botany Staff Meeting, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Botanical Information Inquiries, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Budget - Annual, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Budget - Quarterly, 1947-1957 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Building & Grounds (Mr. Fred Rounds), 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- "C" Miscellaneous, 1945-1956 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Calculator, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Catalogue -, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- 1951 Catalogues (Box 1, Folder 17)
- 1950 Catalog (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Civil Service, 1940-1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Courses, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- "D" Miscellaneous, 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Departmental Requirements, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Director of Admissions, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Draft Deferment Information, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "E" Miscellaneous, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Education, 1949-1952 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Emergency Facilities (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Employment Possibilities, 1944-1949 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Enrollment Data, 1947-1951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Equipment (Box 1, Folder 30)
- "F" Miscellaneous, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Faculty Executive Committee, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Faculty Personnel Policies, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Field Trips, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Fisher Scientific Company, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- "G" Miscellaneous, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Garden Projects, 1947-1953 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- G.I. Regulations - For Equipment, Books, etc. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Graduate Applications, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Letters of Recommendation, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Graduate Applications, 1952-1953 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Graduate Assistants, 1946-1949 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Graduate Examination, Announcements, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Graduate School, 1949-1955 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Grant In Aid, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Thesis Specifications, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Graham, John W & Co., 1938-1950 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- "H" Miscellaneous, 1945-1952 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Hatch, W.R., Chair., Div. of Biological Sciences, 1943-1951 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Herbarium, 1948-1952 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- E.H. Hopkins, 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- "I" Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 52)
- International Botanical Congress, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Isotopes Research - Operations, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- "J" Miscellaneous, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Journal Vouchers, 1949-1954 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- "K" Miscellaneous, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Key Listings, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- "L" Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Library, 1943-1952 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Library Committee on Location of Serials, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- "M" Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Microscopic Equipment, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Military Service, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- "N" Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Non-Faculty Personnel - Lloyd G. Everest, Dir., 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- "O" Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Openings, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- "P" Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Pettibone, Carl - Business Manager & Comptroller, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Photographic Department, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Placement Bureau - W.M. Bristol, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Prairie Strip Adm., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- President, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Prospective Undergraduates, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Publicity, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Purchasing Office, 1944-1952 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Quarter System, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- "R" Miscellaneous, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Registrar (Chambers), 1944-1951 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Registrar: Grade Reports, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Review of General College Requirements, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Rempel, J., Coor. of General Education at WSC, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Requisitions Equipment - Numerically, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- "S" Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Sandberg, R.S., 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Scholarships, 1946-1952 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Schedule of Courses, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Science Hall - Floor Plan, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Scientific Supplies, 1939-1952 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- 2410 Slide Allocation, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Seminars, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Slide Lists Available, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- WSC Staff Bulletins -, Jan. 9, 1953 thru Dec. 1954 (Box 2, Folder 94)
- S.T. Stephenson, Dean of Faculty, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 95)
- Summer School, 1940-1952 (Box 2, Folder 96)
- Student Book Corp., 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 97)
- "T" Miscellaneous, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 98)
- Thesis Committees, 1948-1951 (Box 2, Folder 99)
- Time Slip Payroll - Botany, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 100)
- Travel, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 101)
- Travel Authorizations Approved, 1949-1957 (Box 2, Folder 102)
- Travel Vouchers Submitted, 1950-1956 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- "U" Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 104)
- Utilities & Construc., Sherman Markley, Supt., 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 105)
- U.S. Dept. of Agriculture, 1938-1949 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- Visual Aids, 1948-1952 (Box 2, Folder 107)
- "V" Miscellaneous, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 108)
- "W" Miscellaneous, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 109)
- War Food Administration (Box 2, Folder 110)
- Weed Killers 2-4-D, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 111)
- Requisitions #1-50 Numerical, Supplies & Operations, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 112)
- Requisitions #51-100 Numerical, Supplies & Operations, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 113)